# **Muhammad Ahmad Khan**

Software Engineer | Developer Advocate

Website: mahmadkhan.com

Summary

Email: rmahmadkhan@icloud.com LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/rmahmadkhan

Phone: +923216906520

I'm a full-stack mobile developer building (and occasionally designing) exceptional iOS and Android apps for ~4 years. I have developed and architectured over 20 apps from scratch and pushed them live on AppStore/PlayStore. I've had the privilege of working with multiple startups over the time building products having high user experience and performance. Being a tech evangelist, I've been a part of different tech communities like <u>GDG</u>, <u>GDSC</u>, <u>WTM</u> as a community manager, speaker or member.

### Skillset

- Languages & frameworks: Flutter, Dart, iOS, Android, Swift, Java, Python, JavaScript, TypeScript, Node.js
- DevOps: Git, GitHub, Jira, Firebase, CI/CD, Basics of Cloud (GCP, AWS), PlayStore/AppStore
- Others: BLOC, Provider, GetX, GoRouter, JSON serialization, MVC, MVVM, TDD, Dependency Injection, Wordpress
- Soft skills: Creative, Organization, Leadership, Fast learner, Growth mindset, Team player

# Work Experience

• RĀNA USA (Remote)

Senior Software Engineer (Project Lead) | Flutter, Node.js

Jan 2024 - Present

- Led the development of high-performance geofencing & time tracking mobile app and web dashboard using Flutter
- Optimized the apps for Android and iOS platforms to ensure seamless performance for background tasks
- Implemented robust security measures to protect sensitive location and time data
- Created a design system that enhanced reusability, streamlined development, and ensured a cohesive user experience
- Provided technical leadership and mentorship to junior developers, fostering a collaborative and innovative work environment

Dubai, UAE (Remote)

Software Engineer (Frontend Lead) | Flutter, Python

Mar 2022 - Dec 2023

- Deliver high-quality, robust production code for Jaldi's iOS, Android & web apps in Flutter & Python
- Build a simple and easy-to-use sales crm allowing managers to reduce cold calling admin work by 80%
- Played a pivotal role in revamping the mvp and later launching in production resulting in increase in paying orgs by over 900%
- Maintain unit tests coverage through Test-driven Development (TDD) on backend in Python
- Provide leadership within engineering department through close collaboration, and code reviews

Cross Code

Lahore, Pakistan

Software Developer | Flutter, Firebase

Jul 2021 - Jun 2022

- Developed, maintained, & shipped production code for 10+ client & in-house mobile apps using Flutter, Firebase & RestAPIs
- Worked in BLOC and Providers state management libraries with GetIt for dependency injection
- Integrated different ad providers like Admob, Unity ads, AppLovin, etc
- Co-authored and published an open-source package, Easy Ads, to combine ads integration for Flutter

# Education

#### University of the Punjab

Lahore, Pakistan

Bachelor of Computer Science

Final-year project: Maveshi (A mobile app to digitize local cattle farms)

Relevant coursework: Cloud Computing, Artificial Intelligence, Computer Vision, Mobile Computing, Enterprise Application Development, Analysis of Algorithms, OOP, DSA, Calculus I-II, Linear Algebra, etc.

#### Community Experience

• Google for Developers

Pakistan

GDG Organizer (a)GDG Live Pakistan

Jul 2021 - Present

- Connecting digital Pakistan through online/onsite community events & networking sessions
- Building a community of 20,000+ folks collectively on multiple platforms
- Onboarding speakers & partners by leading community relations and partnerships for the chapter
- Implementing marketing strategies to increase brand recognition and social media engagements

• Flutter Lahore

Lahore, Pakistan

Community Organizer

Feb 2022 - Present

Flutter Lahore is a local community meetup group with a focus on helping developers in Flutter, Firebase, and Google Cloud

- Leading the chapter and organizing different events and workshops
- Building a local community ecosystem for Flutter developers in Lahore & surroundings

# • Google for Developers

Lahore, Pakistan

GDSC Lead @GDSC PUCIT

Jul 2020 - Jul 2021

Google Developer Student Clubs (GDSC) are university based community groups for students interested in Google developer technologies

- Lead a team for planning & hosting different workshops onsite in campus and online
- Made an impact by guiding & supporting students to learn new skills and get hands-on experience with Google technologies

## • Speaker at multiple tech conferences, workshops, and bootcamps

# **Projects**

DMS

iOS, Android, Web dashboard, Website

A comprehensive employee management tool that uses geofencing for automated check-ins and live location tracking. It features a role-based dashboard for admins to easily manage companies, employees, and work hours.

Jaldi

iOS, Android, Web dashboard, Website

A sales crm to manage your leads, providing a workflow for agents to contact leads coming from Facebook, web forms, etc. Jaldi comes with a web-based dashboard for managers and mobile apps (iOS, Android) for sales agents.

PlayOn101

iOS, Android, Website

Playon101 allows sports players of all ages to find someone to practice with on a daily basis. Partnerships with local sports clubs throughout the country enables a sports player to practice with multiple teams in a given week, improving their overall game. Advanced implementations include social sign-in, maps, deep-linking, and push notifications.

• Tatreez Mockups

A tailoring app for Arabic users. Users can select and order the product based on the customization they want and also save their measurements. Advanced implementations include social sign-in, maps, payments, and push notifications.

• Meal Planner

A meal app that suggests a user a meal plan for a whole day for 4 weeks. Users can track progress and make a shopping list inside the app from the suggested meals. Advanced implementations include push notification reminders.

### Certifications

• The Complete Flutter Development Bootcamp with Dart by Dr. Angela Yu

Certificate

• **Python for Everybody** by University of Michigan

Certificate

iOS

• Java for Android by Vanderbilt University

Certificate

• Android App Components - Intents, Activities, and Broadcast Receivers by Vanderbilt University

Certificate

### Languages

• English (Bilingual proficiency)

• Urdu (Native/Bilingual proficiency)

• Hindi (Verbal proficiency)

Punjabi (Native/Bilingual proficiency)